bikemap.net 2018-09-03

# Privacy Policy | Bikemap - Your bike routes

This privacy policy clarifies the type, scope and purpose of the processing of personal data (hereinafter referred to as "data") within the online offering of Bikemap GmbH. The online offering includes related websites, applications (including apps for iOS and Android), features and content, also external online presences, such as social media profiles (collectively referred to as "online offering"). With regard to the terminology used, e.g. "Processing" or "Responsible Officer", we refer to the definitions in Article 4 of the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR).

##### Responsible Officer

##### Types of processed data

  * Inventory data (e.g. name, place of residence, date of birth, gender).
  * Contact information (e.g. email).
  * Content data (e.g. routes, descriptions, pictures).
  * Usage data (e.g. access times).
  * Metadata / communication data (e.g. device information, IP addresses).

##### Categories of affected persons

Visitors and users of the online offering as well as the apps (in the following, we refer to the affected persons as "users").

##### Purpose of processing

  * Provision and continuous improvement of the online and app offering, its functions and content.
  * Answering support requests properly and communicating with users of the online and app offering.
  * Timely provision of up-to-date security measures and technologies, not only in relation to personal user data.
  * Measurement and analysis of the usage of the online offering, including but not limited to reach, demographics and preferences of users to better adapt the online and app offering.

##### Terms used

"Personal data" means any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person (hereinafter the "data subject"); a natural person is considered as identifiable, which can be identified directly or indirectly, in particular by means of assignment to an identifier such as a name, to an identification number, to location data, to an online identifier (e.g. cookie) or to one or more special features, that express the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of this natural person.

"Processing" means any process or series of operations associated with personal data, whether performed with or without the aid of automated procedures, which covers a wide range of virtually all data handling.

"Pseudonymisation" means the processing of personal data in such a way that the personal data can no longer be assigned to a specific data subject without additional information being provided, provided that such additional information is kept separate and subject to technical and organizational measures to ensure that the personal data should not be assigned to an identified or identifiable natural person.

"Profiling" means any kind of automated processing of personal data which consists in using that personal data to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to a natural person, in particular aspects relating to job performance, economic situation, health, to analyze or predict personal preferences, interests, reliability, behavior, location or change of location of that natural person.

"Responsible person" means the natural or legal person, public authority, body or body that decides, alone or in concert with others, on the purposes and means of processing personal data.

"Processor" means a natural or legal person, public authority or other body that processes personal data on behalf of the controller. 

##### Relevant legal sources

In accordance with Art. 13 GDPR, we communicate the legal basis of our data processing. Unless the legal basis is mentioned otherwise in the data protection declaration, the following applies: The legal basis for obtaining consent is Article 6 (1) lit. a and Art. 7 DSGVO, the legal basis for the processing for the performance of our services and the execution of contractual measures as well as the response to inquiries is Art. 6 (1) lit. b DSGVO, the legal basis for processing in order to fulfill our legal obligations is Art. 6 (1) lit. c DSGVO, and the legal basis for processing in order to safeguard our legitimate interests is Article 6 (1) lit. f DSGVO. In the event that vital interests of the data subject or another natural person require the processing of personal data, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. d DSGVO is the legal basis.

##### Safety measures

We take appropriate technical measures in accordance with Art. 32 GDPR, taking into account the state of the art, the implementation costs and the nature, scope, circumstances and purposes of the processing as well as the different probability and severity of the risk to the rights and freedoms of natural persons and organizational measures to ensure a level of protection appropriate to the risk.

Measures include, in particular, ensuring the confidentiality, integrity and availability of data by controlling physical access to the data, as well as their access, input, disclosure, availability and separation. We have also set up procedures to ensure data subject rights, data deletion and data vulnerability. Furthermore, we consider the protection of personal data already in the development, or selection of hardware, software and procedures, according to the principle of data protection through technology design and privacy-friendly default settings (Article 25 DSGVO). 

##### Collaboration with data processors and third parties

If, in the context of our processing, we disclose data to other persons and companies (contract processors or third parties), transmit them to them or otherwise grant access to the data, this will only be done on the basis of a legal permission (e.g. if a transmission of the data to third parties, as required by payment service providers, pursuant to Art. 6 (1) (b) GDPR to fulfill the contract), you have consented to a legal obligation or collaboration is needed to fulfill our legitimate interests (e.g. the use of agents, webhosters). If we commission third parties to process data on the basis of a so-called "processing contract", this is done on the basis of Art. 28 GDPR.

##### Transfers to third countries

If we process data in a third country (i.e. outside the European Union (EU) or the European Economic Area (EEA)) or in the context of the use of third party services or disclosure or transmission of data to third parties, this will only be done if it is to fulfill our (pre-) contractual obligations, on the basis of your consent, on the basis of a legal obligation or on the basis of our legitimate interests. Subject to legal or contractual permissions, we process or have the data processed in a third country only in the presence of the special conditions of Art. 44 et seq. DSGVO. That the processing is e.g. on the basis of specific guarantees, such as the officially recognized level of data protection (e.g. for the US through so-called „Privacy Shield“) or compliance with officially recognized special contractual obligations (so-called "standard contractual clauses").

##### Rights of data subjects

You have the right to ask for confirmation as to whether the data in question is being processed. You also have the right to receive information about this data as well as for further information and a copy of the data in accordance with Art. 15 GDPR.

You have according to Art. 16 DSGVO the right to demand the completion of the data concerning you or the correction of the incorrect data concerning you.

In accordance with Art. 17 GDPR, you have the right to demand that the relevant data be deleted immediately or, alternatively, to require a restriction of the processing of data in accordance with Art. 18 GDPR.

You have the right to demand that the data relating to you, which you have provided to us, be obtained in accordance with Art. 20 GDPR and request their transmission to other persons / entities of your choosing.

According to  Art. 77 DSGVO you have the right to file a complaint with the concerning authority. 

##### Right to withdraw

You have the right to withdraw a previously granted consent in accordance with. Art. 7 §3 DSGVO, with effect for the future.

##### Right to refuse

You can object to the future processing of your data in accordance with Art. 21 GDPR at any time. The objection may in particular be made against processing for direct marketing purposes.

##### Cookies and right to object against direct mails

"Cookies" are small files that are stored on users' computers, different information can be stored within the cookies, and a cookie is primarily used to store information about a user (or the device on which the cookie is stored) or even after their visit to an online offer. Temporary cookies, or "session cookies" or "transient cookies", are cookies that are deleted after a user leaves an online service and closes his browser. For example, the content of a shopping cart in an online shop or a login status can be stored in a cookie. "Persistent" means cookies that remain stored even after the browser has been closed, e.g. the login status can be saved. If the users visits the online offering again after several days, the interests of the users can also be stored in such a cookie, which is then used for e.g. reach measurement or marketing purposes. A "third-party cookie" refers to cookies that are offered by providers other than the person who manages the online offering (otherwise, if it is only their cookies, this is called "first-party cookies").

We can use temporary and permanent cookies and clarify this in the context of our privacy policy.

If users do not want cookies stored on their computer, they will be asked to disable the option in their browser's system settings. Saved cookies can be deleted in the system settings of the browser. The exclusion of cookies can lead to functional restrictions of the online offering of Bikemap GmbH.

A general guide to object to the use of cookies for online marketing purposes can be found in a variety of services, especially in the case of tracking, as explained on the US website <http://optout.aboutads.info/> or the EU site <https://www.youronlinechoices.com/>. Furthermore, the storage of cookies can be suspended by switching them off in the settings of the browser.

Please note that it may not be possible to use all functions of the online offering by Bikemap GmbH, if cookies are turned off partially or completely. 

##### Deletion of data

The data processed by us is deleted or limited in their processing in accordance with Articles 17 and 18 GDPR. Unless explicitly stated in this privacy policy, the data stored by us is deleted as soon as it is no longer required for its respective purpose and the deletion does not conflict with any statutory storage requirements.

If the data must not be deleted out of other and legitimate purposes and / or legal requirements, processing of the data will be restricted as much as possible, i.e. the data will be locked and will not be processed for other purposes. This applies, for example, for data that must be kept for reasons regarding commercial or tax law.

According to legal regulations in Austria the storage duration is 7 years according to § 132 exp. 1 BAO (accounting documents, vouchers / bills, accounts, documents, business papers, statement of income and expenses, etc.), for 22 years in connection with real estate and for 10 years in the case of documents relating to electronically supplied services, telecommunications, broadcasting and television services provided to non-entrepreneurs in EU Member States and for which the Mini-One-Stop-Shop (MOSS) is used. 

##### Business-related processing

In addition we process

  * Contract data (e.g. subject, term, customer category),
  * Payment data (e.g. payment history),

from our customers, prospects and business partners for the purpose of providing contractual services, service and customer care, marketing, advertising and market research.

##### External payment service Stripe

As an external payment service provider, we use Stripe, which enables users and Bikemap to make payment transactions (<https://stripe.com/privacy/>).

As part of the fulfillment of contracts, we set the payment service provider on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b. DSGVO. Incidentally, we set the external payment service provider on the basis of our legitimate interests according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b. DSGVO in order to offer our users effective and secure payment options.

Amongst the data processed by the payment service provider are inventory data, e.g. the name and the address, bank data, such as account numbers or credit card numbers, passwords, TANs and checksums, as well as contract, summary and recipient-related information. The information is required to complete the transactions. However, the data entered will only be processed and stored by the payment service provider. That means we do not receive any account or credit card information, but only information with regards to payment success. The data may be transmitted by the payment service provider to credit reporting agencies. This transmission serves purposes of identification of credit worthiness. For this we refer to the terms and conditions and privacy policy of the payment service provider.

For the payment transactions, the terms and conditions and the privacy notices of the payment services, which are available within the respective website or transaction application apply. We also refer to these for further information and assertion of rights of withdrawal, information and other data subjects. 

##### Hosting

The hosting services we use are for the purpose of providing the following services: infrastructure and platform services, computing capacity, storage and database services, security and technical maintenance services we use to operate the online offering of Bikemap GmbH.

Here we, or our hosting provider, process inventory data, contact data, content data, contract data, usage data, meta and communication data of customers, interested parties and visitors to this online offering on the basis of our legitimate interests in an efficient and secure manner of this online offering acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO & Art. 28 DSGVO (conclusion of contract processing contract). 

##### Collection of access data and log files

We, or our hosting provider, collects on the basis of our legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO data at every access to the server on which this service is located (so-called server log files). The access data includes name of the retrieved web page, file, date and time of retrieval, amount of data transferred, message about successful retrieval, browser type and version, the user's operating system, referrer URL (the previously visited page), IP address and the requesting provider.

Logfile information is stored for security purposes (for example, to investigate abusive or fraudulent activities) for a maximum of 7 days and then deleted. Data whose further retention is required for evidential purposes shall be exempted from the cancellation until final clarification of the incident. 

##### Provision of contractual services

We process inventory data (e.g. names and addresses as well as contact information of users), contract data (e.g. services used, names of contacts, payment information) for the purpose of fulfilling our contractual obligations and services in accordance with Art. Art. 6 para. 1 lit b. DSGVO. The entries marked as mandatory in online forms are required for the conclusion of the contract.

As part of the use of our online services, we store the IP address and the time of each user action. The storage is based on our legitimate interests, as well as the user's protection against misuse and other unauthorized use. A transfer of this data to third parties does not take place, unless it is necessary for the prosecution of our claims or there is a legal obligation in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c DSGVO.

We process usage data (e.g. the visited web pages of our online offering, interest in our products) and content data (e.g. entries in the contact form or user profile) for advertising purposes in a user profile to inform the user - e.g. displaying product instructions based on their previously used services.

The deletion of the data takes place after expiration of legal warranty and comparable obligations, all while the necessity of the storage of the data is checked every three years; in the case of legal archiving obligations, the deletion takes place after its expiration. Information in the customer's account remains until it is deleted. 

##### Administration, financial accounting, office organization, contact management

We process data in the context of administrative tasks and organization of our business, financial accounting and compliance with legal obligations, such as archiving. We process the same data that we process in the course of rendering our contractual services. The processing principles are Art. 6 para. 1 lit. c. DSGVO, Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO. The processing affects customers, prospects, business partners and website visitors. The purpose and interest in processing lies in administration, financial accounting, office organization, data archiving. That is, tasks that serve to maintain our business, perform our duties and provide our services. The deletion of the data in terms of contractual performance and contractual communication corresponds to the information provided in these processing activities.

We disclose or transmit data to the financial administration, consultants, such as tax accountants or auditors, and other business agents and payment service providers.

Furthermore, based on our business interests, we store information about suppliers, promoters and other business partners, e.g. for later contact. We generally store this majority of company-related data permanently. 

##### Privacy policy in the application process

We process the applicant data only for the purpose and in the context of the application process in accordance with the legal requirements. The processing of the applicant data takes place in order to fulfill our (pre-) contractual obligations in the context of the application process within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b. DSGVO Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO if the data processing e.g. is required for us in the context of legal proceedings.

The application process requires applicants to provide us with the applicant data. The necessary applicant data result from the job descriptions and basically include the information on the person, postal and contact addresses and the application documents, such as cover letter, CV and certificates. In addition, applicants can voluntarily provide us with additional information.

By submitting the application to us, the applicants agree to the processing of their data for the purposes of the application process in accordance with the nature and scope set forth in this Privacy Policy.

Insofar as special categories of personal data within the meaning of Art. 9 (1) GDPR are voluntarily communicated within the framework of the application procedure, their processing is additionally carried out in accordance with Art. 9 (2) lit. b DSGVO (e.g. health information such as disability or ethnic origin). Insofar as special categories of personal data within the meaning of Art. 9 (1) GDPR are requested from applicants in the context of the application procedure, their processing is additionally carried out in accordance with Art. 9 para. 2 lit. a GDPR (for example health data, if necessary for the profession).

Applicants can send us their applications via e-mail. However, please note that e-mails are generally not sent in encrypted form and that applicants themselves must provide encryption. We can therefore take no responsibility for the transmission of the application between the sender and the reception on our server and therefore recommend using postal delivery. Instead of applying via the online form and e-mail, applicants still have the opportunity to send us the application via postal service.

The data provided by the applicants may be further processed by us in the event of a successful application for employment purposes. Otherwise, if the application for a job offer is not successful, the applicants' data will be deleted. Applicants' data will also be deleted if an application is withdrawn, which the applicants are entitled to at any time.

The cancellation is subject to a legitimate cancellation of the candidate, after the expiration of a period of six months, so that we can answer any follow-up questions to the application and meet our obligations under the Equal Treatment Act. Invoices for any reimbursement of travel expenses are archived in accordance with the tax regulations. 

##### Talent Pool

Within the scope of the application, we offer applicants the opportunity to be admitted to our "Talent Pool" for a period of two years on the basis of a consent within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) (b) and 7 of the GDPR.

The application documents in the Talent Pool are processed solely as part of future job advertisements and job search and will be destroyed at the latest after the deadline. Candidates are informed that their consent to be admitted to the talent pool is voluntary, has no influence on the current application process and that they can revoke this consent at any time in the future and declare an objection within the meaning of Art. 21 GDPR. 

##### Registering a user profile with Bikemap

Users can create a user account. As part of the registration, the necessary mandatory information is communicated to the users and on the basis of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b DSGVO processed for purposes of providing the user account. The processed data include in particular the login information (password and an email address).

The data entered during registration will be used for the purpose of using the offer. Users may be informed by email about offer- or registration-related information, such as changes in the scope of the offer or technical circumstances. If users have terminated their user account, their data within the user account will be deleted (except for statutory retention obligations). It is the responsibility of the users to secure their data upon termination before the end of the contract. We are entitled to irretrievably delete all user data stored during the term of the contract.

Alternatively, it is also possible to register and log in to the website using a third-party account (Facebook or Google). When accessing the site through a third-party account, information is collected that is provided according to the privacy settings of the third-party account. This information includes your first name, last name, email address and profile picture. The information is collected by the third-party account vendor and made available to us under its privacy policy. 

##### Contacting Bikemap GmbH

When contacting us (for example, by contact form, email, telephone or via social media) the information provided by the user will be used to process the contact request in accordance with Art. 6 para. 1 lit. b) DSGVO. User information can be stored in a Customer Relationship Management System ("CRM System") or comparable tools.

We delete the requests, if they are no longer required. We check the necessity every two years; Furthermore, the legal archiving obligations apply. 

##### CRM System Zendesk

We use Zendesk's CRM system, Zendesk, Inc., 989 Market Street # 300, San Francisco, CA 94102, USA, to handle requests from users faster and more efficiently (legitimate interest in accordance with Art. 6 Para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO).

Zendesk is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, providing an additional guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOjeAAG&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TOjeAAG&status=Active)).

Zendesk uses the users' data only for the technical processing of inquiries and does not pass them on to third parties. The use of Zendesk requires at least the specification of a correct e-mail address. A pseudonymous use is possible. During the processing of service requests it may be necessary to collect further data (name, address). The use of Zendesk is optional and serves to improve and speed up our customer and user service.

If users disagree with Zendesk's data collection and data storage in the external system, we offer alternative contact options for submitting service requests by email, phone or postal service.

Further information is available to users in the Zendesk Privacy Policy: <https://www.zendesk.com/company/customers-partners/privacy-policy/>. 

##### Comments and posts

If users leave comments or other contributions, their IP addresses may be stored for 7 days, based on our legitimate interests within the meaning of Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO. This is done for the safety of the Bikemap GmbH and our users, e.g. if someone leaves in comments and contributions of unlawful content (insults, prohibited political propaganda, etc.), and therefore requires further administrative or legal action by Bikemap GmbH, or other (third) parties.

Furthermore, we reserve the right, in accordance with our legitimate interests. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f. DSGVO to process the information of users for the purpose of spam detection. 

##### Newsletter

With the following information we inform you about the contents of our newsletter as well as the registration, dispatch and statistical evaluation procedures and clarify your rights of objection.  
By subscribing to our newsletter, you agree to the receipt and the procedures described.  
Content of the newsletter: We send you newsletters, emails and other electronic notifications with advertising information (hereinafter "newsletter") only with the consent of the recipient or a legal permission. Where in the context of a newsletter registration where the contents that are described concretely apply, in general our newsletter contains information on our online offering and the Bikemap GmbH in general.

Double opt-in and logging: Registration for our newsletter is done in a so-called double-opt-in procedure. That after registration, you will receive an email asking you to confirm your registration. This confirmation is necessary so that nobody can register with external e-mail addresses. The registration for the newsletter will be logged in order to prove the registration process according to the legal requirements. This includes the storage of the login and the confirmation time, as well as the IP address. Likewise, changes to your data stored with the shipping service provider will be logged.

Credentials: To subscribe to the newsletter, it is sufficient to provide your email address.

The dispatch of the newsletter and the related performance measurement is based on the consent of the recipient according to Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a, Art. 7 DSGVO i.V.m. § 107 Abs. 2 TKG or on the basis of the legal permission acc. Section 107 (2) and the like 3 TKG.

The logging of the registration process is based on our legitimate interests in accordance with. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO. Our interest lies in the use of a user-friendly and secure newsletter system, which serves both our business interests and the expectations of the users and also allows us to prove our consent.

Termination / Revocation - You may terminate the receipt of our newsletter at any time, i.e. revoke your consent. A link to cancel the newsletter can be found at the end of each newsletter. We may save the submitted email addresses for up to three years based on our legitimate interests before we delete them to provide prior consent. The processing of this data is limited to the purpose of a possible defense against claims. An individual request for cancellation is possible at any time, provided that at the same time the former existence of a consent is confirmed. 

##### Newsletter - Mailjet

The newsletter is sent by Mailjet SAS, 13-13 bis, rue de l'Aubrac, 75012 Paris, France. The privacy policy of the shipping service provider can be viewed here: https://www.mailjet.de/privacy-policy/. The shipping service provider is based on our legitimate interests acc. Art. 6 para. 1 lit. f DSGVO and a contract processing agreement acc. Art. 28 (3) sentence 1 DSGVO.

The shipping service provider may use the data of the recipients in pseudonymous form, i.e. without reference to a user, to optimize or improve their own services, e.g. for the technical optimization of shipping and the presentation of newsletters or for statistical purposes. However, the shipping service provider does not use the data of our newsletter recipients to address them themselves or to pass the data on to third parties.

##### Newsletter - Success Measurement

The newsletters contain a so-called "web-beacon", i.e. a pixel-sized file that is retrieved from the server when the newsletter is opened by our server or, if we use a shipping service provider, in the course of this retrieval information about the browser and your system, as well as your IP address and time of retrieval.

This information is used to improve the technical performance of services based on their specifications or audience and their reading habits, based on their locations (which can be determined using the IP address) or access times. Statistical surveys also include determining if the newsletters will be opened, when they will be opened and which links will be clicked. For technical reasons, this information can be assigned to the individual newsletter recipients. However, it is neither our goal nor, if used, that of the shipping service provider to observe individual users. The evaluations serve us much more to recognize the reading habits of our users and to adapt our content to them or to send different content according to the interests of our users. 

##### Google Analytics

Based on our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offer within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. DSGVO), we use Google Analytics, a web analytics service provided by Google LLC ("Google"). Google uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about users' use of the online offer is usually transmitted to and stored by Google on servers in the United States.

Google is certified under the Privacy Shield Agreement, which provides a guarantee to comply with European privacy legislation ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)).

Google will use this information on our behalf to evaluate the use of our online offering by users, to compile reports on the activities within this online offer and to provide us with further services related to the use of this online offer and the internet usage. In this case, pseudonymous usage profiles of the users can be created from the processed data.

We only use Google Analytics with activated IP anonymization. This means that the IP address of the users will be shortened by Google within member states of the European Union or in other contracting states of the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Only in exceptional cases will the full IP address be sent to a Google server in the US and shortened there.

The IP address submitted by the user's browser will not be merged with other data provided by Google. Users can prevent the storage of cookies by setting their browser software accordingly. Users may also prevent Google‘s collection of the data generated by the cookie itself and data generated related to the use of the online offering and the processing of such data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plug-in available at the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>.

For more information about Google's data usage, settings and disparaging options, please read Google's Privacy Policy (<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>) and Google's Ads Settings (<https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>). 

##### Integration of services and contents of third parties

Based on our legitimate interests (i.e. interest in the analysis, optimization and economic operation of our online offering within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. DSGVO), we make use of content or services offered by third-party providers in order to provide their content and services, such as including videos or fonts (collectively referred to as "content").

This always presupposes that the third-party providers of this content perceive the IP address of the users, since they could not send the content to their browser without the IP address. The IP address is therefore required for the presentation of this content. We endeavor to use only content whose respective providers use the IP address solely for the delivery of the content. Third parties may also use so-called pixel tags (invisible graphics, also referred to as "web beacons") for statistical or marketing purposes. The "pixel tags" can be used to evaluate information such as visitor traffic on the pages of this website. The pseudonymous information may also be stored in cookies on the user's device and may include, but is not limited to, technical information about the browser and operating system, referring web pages, visit time, and other information regarding the use of our online offering. 

##### Google ReCaptcha

We use the function to detect bots, e.g. when entering into online forms ("ReCaptcha") of the provider Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheater Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA. Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>  

##### Maptoolkit

We include the maps of the service "Maptoolkit" of Toursprung GmbH ([https://www.toursprung.com](https://www.toursprung.com/)). To the best of our knowledge, Maptoolkit's data is used solely for the purpose of displaying the map features and caching the selected settings. This data may include, but is not limited to, users' IP addresses and location data, but they are not collected without their consent (usually as part of their mobile device settings). The data can be processed in the USA. For more information, see the Maptoolkit Privacy Policy: <https://www.toursprung.com/privacy>.

##### Updates to the Privacy Policy

Users of the online offering of Bikemap GmbH are required to regularly inform themselves about the content of the privacy policy. As soon as the changes in the data processing carried out as part of the online offering make it necessary, the privacy policy will be adjusted accordingly. Should the changes require an action by the user of the online offering of Bikemap GmbH (for example, consent), timely and appropriate information will be provided.

###### Last update: May 23, 2018
